myvikingjourney.com 2018-08-27

# Privacy Policy - Viking Cruises

##### **Privacy Policy**

Viking Cruises is committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to the Viking Cruises website and governs its data collection, usage and services. This privacy policy also discloses how we collect, protect, use and share information gathered about you on our website. 

* * *

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

You can use our website without divulging any personally identifiable information including your email address. Our website does not collect personally identifiable information about individuals except when such individuals specifically provide such information on a voluntary basis, such as when registering at our website, requesting a brochure or video, or accessing our “request a reservation” or “book now” feature. Viking Cruises uses such information collected to provide the products or services you request, to improve and customize the content you see, and to contact you about special promotions and new products if requested. 

* * *

**PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Viking Cruises collects personally identifiable information on the site. Personal information includes, among other things, a user’s name, address, business address, telephone number, business telephone number, and email address. Fields in which we collect such required information are marked with an asterisk (*). We also may ask you for your date of birth and information about your interests so that we can combine such information with the information described above. We use that information so that both you and we can take advantage of the interactivity of the internet to provide you with services and offers. You may always choose whether to respond or not. We also receive personally identifiable information when you apply for a job in the “employment” section of the site. Any such information gathered through that section will be used solely to evaluate whether your background and experience make you a candidate for a career with Viking Cruises. 

* * *

**NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**

In addition to personal information, Viking Cruises may also gather non-personally identifiable information, which may be used by Viking Cruises. Generally, “non-personally identifiable information” means information that is collected through “traffic data” and may entail the use of “cookies,” “IP addresses,” “pixel tags” or other numeric codes used to identify a computer or monitor how or when a user accesses the site or communications. 

* * *

**PIXEL TAGS AND COOKIES**

We use an email delivery and marketing company to send emails. Pixel tags and cookies are used in those email messages and at our website to help us measure the effectiveness of our marketing and how visitors use our site.Pixel tags (sometimes also called “clear GIFs”) are small graphic files, invisible to the human eye, which allow websites or other online services to track users. Viking Cruises and our third-party advertising company uses pixel tags in HTML-enabled email to track whether (and when) the recipient opened the message. The data on your use of our site may be linked to the Personal Information you have chosen to share with us when you register. Most internet browsers automatically accept cookies. However, you can instruct your browser, by editing its options, to stop accepting cookies or prompt you before accepting a cookie from the sites you visit. If you decide not to accept our cookies, your ability to use some features on our site may be impaired. Certain visitors to our site may have previously received targeted promotional materials relative to the site. Viking Cruises may share site usage information about such visitors with reputable third parties for the purpose of targeting future campaigns and upgrading visitor information used in reporting statistics. Although our marketing company logs the information coming from our site on our behalf, we control how that data may and may not be used. 

* * *

**PAYMENTS**

When you place an order or access your personal information, Viking Cruises uses a secure server. All of your personal information, including credit card number, name, and address, is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology — the industry standard for secure online transactions - and then encrypted into our databases. If you would rather not shop online, you can place your order over the phone by contacting a Viking representative.

* * *

 **CHILDREN**

Viking Cruises does not sell products for purchase by children. If you are under 18, your parents are responsible for approving your use of this site. 

* * *

**PRIVACY AND CHANGE OF CONTROL**

In the event Viking Cruises goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. 

* * *

**CONSENT AND CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

By using this site, you consent to the collection, use and storage of your information by us in the manner described in this Privacy Policy and elsewhere on the site. We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. If this Privacy Policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties. 

* * *

**YOUR COMMENTS ARE APPRECIATED**

If you have any questions or comments regarding our privacy policy or our website, you can send us an email at [webmaster@vikingcruises.com](mailto:webmaster@vikingcruises.com) We also use cookies to improve the performance of our advertising on other websites. Although you may not opt out of receiving online advertisements generally, you may control the collection of data on our site used for targeted [VikingCruises.com](http://vikingcruises.com/) advertising during your visits to other websites. to opt-out of [VikingCruises.com](http://vikingcruises.com/) data collection for targeted advertising on other sites, [click here](http://media.vikingrivercruises.com/optout.html). 

##### **Privacy Policy**

Viking Cruises is committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to the Viking Cruises website and governs its data collection, usage and services. This privacy policy also discloses how we collect, protect, use and share information gathered about you on our website. 

* * *

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

You can use our website without divulging any personally identifiable information including your email address. Our website does not collect personally identifiable information about individuals except when such individuals specifically provide such information on a voluntary basis, such as when registering at our website, requesting a brochure or video, or accessing our “request a reservation” or “book now” feature. Viking Cruises uses such information collected to provide the products or services you request, to improve and customize the content you see, and to contact you about special promotions and new products if requested. 

* * *

**PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Viking Cruises collects personally identifiable information on the site. Personal information includes, among other things, a user’s name, address, business address, telephone number, business telephone number, and email address. Fields in which we collect such required information are marked with an asterisk (*). We also may ask you for your date of birth and information about your interests so that we can combine such information with the information described above. We use that information so that both you and we can take advantage of the interactivity of the internet to provide you with services and offers. You may always choose whether to respond or not. We also receive personally identifiable information when you apply for a job in the “employment” section of the site. Any such information gathered through that section will be used solely to evaluate whether your background and experience make you a candidate for a career with Viking Cruises. 

* * *

**NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**

In addition to personal information, Viking Cruises may also gather non-personally identifiable information, which may be used by Viking Cruises. Generally, “non-personally identifiable information” means information that is collected through “traffic data” and may entail the use of “cookies,” “IP addresses,” “pixel tags” or other numeric codes used to identify a computer or monitor how or when a user accesses the site or communications. 

* * *

**PIXEL TAGS AND COOKIES**

We use an email delivery and marketing company to send emails. Pixel tags and cookies are used in those email messages and at our website to help us measure the effectiveness of our marketing and how visitors use our site.Pixel tags (sometimes also called “clear GIFs”) are small graphic files, invisible to the human eye, which allow websites or other online services to track users. Viking Cruises and our third-party advertising company uses pixel tags in HTML-enabled email to track whether (and when) the recipient opened the message. The data on your use of our site may be linked to the Personal Information you have chosen to share with us when you register. Most internet browsers automatically accept cookies. However, you can instruct your browser, by editing its options, to stop accepting cookies or prompt you before accepting a cookie from the sites you visit. If you decide not to accept our cookies, your ability to use some features on our site may be impaired. Certain visitors to our site may have previously received targeted promotional materials relative to the site. Viking Cruises may share site usage information about such visitors with reputable third parties for the purpose of targeting future campaigns and upgrading visitor information used in reporting statistics. Although our marketing company logs the information coming from our site on our behalf, we control how that data may and may not be used. 

* * *

**PAYMENTS**

When you place an order or access your personal information, Viking Cruises uses a secure server. All of your personal information, including credit card number, name, and address, is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology — the industry standard for secure online transactions - and then encrypted into our databases. If you would rather not shop online, you can place your order over the phone by contacting a Viking representative.

* * *

 **CHILDREN**

Viking Cruises does not sell products for purchase by children. If you are under 18, your parents are responsible for approving your use of this site. 

* * *

**PRIVACY AND CHANGE OF CONTROL**

In the event Viking Cruises goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. 

* * *

**CONSENT AND CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

By using this site, you consent to the collection, use and storage of your information by us in the manner described in this Privacy Policy and elsewhere on the site. We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. If this Privacy Policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties. 

* * *

**YOUR COMMENTS ARE APPRECIATED**

If you have any questions or comments regarding our privacy policy or our website, you can send us an email at [webmaster@vikingcruises.com](mailto:webmaster@vikingcruises.com) We also use cookies to improve the performance of our advertising on other websites. Although you may not opt out of receiving online advertisements generally, you may control the collection of data on our site used for targeted [VikingCruises.com](http://vikingcruises.com/) advertising during your visits to other websites. to opt-out of [VikingCruises.com](http://vikingcruises.com/) data collection for targeted advertising on other sites, [click here](http://media.vikingrivercruises.com/optout.html).
